JULIA FORTUNY WOLLNY

Data analyst

> Berlin |

| fortunyjulia@gmail.com |

| 0179 6352151 |

| juliafor.github.io/juliafortuny

Data analyst with a background in customer service and managing concert tours. Experienced in project planning and dealing with stakeholders of different backgrounds. Skilled in written and spoken communication, presenting results and coming up with good ideas. On a constant quest to learn.

DATA EXPERIENCE

Rockbuster Top Customer Project (CareerFoundry Data Analytics Program)

- Goal: find the most loval customers of a movie rental company. Analyse demographics & spending behaviour across customer base.
- Process: extracted data from 16-table SQL database, cleaned, summarised, analysed in PostgreSQL, including filtering, subqueries, joins and CTEs.
- Outcome: compelling Tableau presentation drilling down to the top 5 clients.

Instacart Basket Analysis (CareerFoundry Data Analytics Program)

- Goal: help an online grocery shop better understand purchasing behaviours and segment customer base to build a more targeted marketing strategy.
- Process: analyse historical data (34 million rows) in Python, derive new variables, define customer profiles and create visualizations.
- Outcome: report with data flow, visualizations + answers to business questions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Customer support at Brunobett.de (Berlin), June 2021 – present Supporting 300+ customers per month & pitching new potential clients.

Customer support & communication at Recordsale.de (Berlin), 2020 – 2021 Solved 800+ customer requests, organized & held 8+ meetings with team & management each month to ensure operational efficiency.

Booker & tour manager, self-employed (Berlin, Beijing), 2015 – 2020 Created touring opportunities for Chinese indie artists, enabling 12+ bands to tour Europe and 15 European countries to discover alternative music from the PRC.

Customer service specialist at Booking.com (Berlin), 2016 – 2019 Resolved 700+ requests & complaints a month by efficiently deploying internal CRM system & procedures.

Booker & tour manager (Europe) at Maybe Mars Music (Beijing), 2012 – 2014 Developed international touring plans for 10+ artists such as Carsick Cars, P.K.14 and Chui Wan.

Copy editor & translator at Xinhua News Agency (Beijing), 2008 – 2012 Corrected or translated 300+ news stories each month from English to Spanish.

Translator at China Central Television (Beijing), 2007 – 2008 Translated 350+ news stories a month for TV from English to Spanish.

Account manager at Tulip Mega Media (Beijing), 2006 – 2007 Sold and marketed outdoor advertising space on high-definition LED screens.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Program CareerFoundry, 2021

MOOC Managing the Arts

Mentored Open Online Course Leuphana Digital School & Goethe Institut e.V., 2016

HSK Chinese Proficiency Certificate (level 6), 2010

MA Communication, Culture & Production

Anglia Polytechnic University, 2004

BA (Hons) Film Studies & Drama Anglia Polytechnic University, 2002

SKILLS

- ✓ Preparing + analysing data
- ✓ Data visualization + storytelling
- ✓ SQL for data analytics
- ✓ Python for data analytics
- ✓ Basic HTML
- ✓ Planning + organizing meetings
- ✓ Project planning + management
- ✓ Communicating + presenting
- ✓ Customer support
- ✓ Languages: English, German, Spanish, French, Catalan (all fluent)
- + Chinese (B2)

TOOLS

Excel

Tableau

PostgreSQL G Suite

Python

Trello

Zendesk

Confluence